“Come to me.” With those powerful words,
Jesus offered an invitation.
He opened a door, or more than that,
he became the door into the life
our hearts have always longed for.
A life made right-side up.
A life lived in real
relationship with God.
Jesus did not only tell
us about that life,
he showed us what it looks like.
He invited us to come to him,
learn from him and become fully alive.
This is the hope at the
heart of every church,
that we would encourage one
another along this Jesus Journey.
As our beliefs, our experience and
our everyday practices become more
aligned with the life of Jesus,
we enjoy more of the relationship
with God that Jesus so clearly knew.
But every church eventually
encounters an important question.
Where are we now?
Anyone who has hiked
into pristine backcountry
understands why that matters.
We would not think of heading
off without a trail map.
But before we can even begin using the map
to get to where we want to go,
we first need to know
where we are on that map.
Only then can we plot the journey.
“You are here.”
Yet, when it comes to
becoming more like Jesus,
that starting point is often missing.
We can measure attendance,
programs and many other
signs of church activity.
Those things matter, but they do
not necessarily tell us where we
are in the deeper journey
of becoming like Jesus.
And when we cannot see where we are,
it's easy to focus on improving
church structures and programs,
hoping they will somehow
produce deeper transformation.
We are often disappointed.
This is what the Jesus Journey is for.
It helps individuals and churches
see more clearly where they are
now in their journey of
becoming more like Jesus.
It takes the life of
Jesus as our true north,
what he believed, what he
experienced and how he lived in
relationship with his Father.
Then, it helps us reflect
honestly on our own
beliefs, experiences and practices.
This is not about being judged.
This is not about being compared.
It is about discovering where
Jesus is already meeting us.
Right where we are is the
edge of his invitation.
From there, he calls us forward
to trust him more deeply,
to experience more of his presence,
to reflect his character
and to serve in his way.
Seeing where we are helps
us embrace the invitation
and the adventure ahead.
Welcome to the Jesus Journey.